Women's Center Records UA156
Tufts Archival Research Center
- Publications, pamphlets, and women's organizations, 1964 -- 2010; UA156.003; 4.1 Linear Feet
  - Ain't I a woman?, 1972-02-11; UA156.003.006.00015 (Box data_value_missing_6a278a10ccb405ecd731790260bd5f8c)
    Volume, issue
    2, 6
  - Ain't I a woman?, 1973; UA156.003.006.00016 (Box 6)
    4, 1
  - Alcohol abuse and women: A guide to getting help, 1976; UA156.003.006.00017 (Box 6)
    From the National Institute on Alcohol Abuse and Alcoholism.
  - Amazon expedition: A lesbian feminist anthology, 1973; UA156.003.006.00018; Birkby, Phyllis; Harris, Bertha; Johnston, Jill, 1929-2010; Newton, Esther; O'Wyatt, Jane (Box 6)
  - Apple: A journal of women's sexuality and erotica, 1976; UA156.003.006.00019 (Box 6)
    A publication of the Seattle Institute of Sex Therapy (SISTER).
    Issue
    1
  - Azalea: A magazine by and for Third World lesbians, 1980 -- 1981; UA156.003.006.00020 (Box 6)
    Vol. 3, No. 3 and Vol. 4, No. 1.
  - Birth control handbook, 1990; UA156.003.006.00021; Cherniak, Donna (Box 6)
  - A book about birth control, 1980; UA156.003.006.00022; Cherniak, Donna (Box 6)
  - Books on women: A catalog from Arno Press, 1975; UA156.003.006.00023 (Box 6)
  - Books to build a new society, 1985; UA156.003.006.00024 (Box data_value_missing_6a278a10ccb405ecd731790260bd5f8c)
  - Boston women's poetry anthology, 1970; UA156.003.006.00025; Fenton, Elizabeth (Box 6)
    A Bread and Roses publication.
  - Bridges: A journal for Jewish feminists and our friends, 1994 -- 1995; UA156.003.006.00026 (Box 6)
    Vol. 4, No. 1; Vol. 4, No. 2; and Vol. 5, No. 2.
  - Bridges: A journal for Jewish feminists and our friends, 1996 -- 1997; UA156.003.006.00027 (Box 6)
    Vol. 6, No. 1; and Vol. 6, No. 2.
  - Brown sister, 1977; UA156.003.007.00001 (Box 7)
    A Wellesley College student publication.
    1, 3
  - Chemical use / abuse and the female reproductive system, 1976; UA156.003.007.00002; Gray, Nancy (Box 7)
    2nd revised edition.
  - Child-rearing and women's liberation, 1970; UA156.003.007.00003; Wortis, Sheli (Box 7)
  - Circle one: A woman's beginning guide to self health and sexuality, 1975; UA156.003.007.00004; Campbell, Elizabeth L.; Ziegler, Vicki (Box 7)
  - Class and feminism: A collection of essays from THE FURIES, 1974; UA156.003.007.00005; Bunch, Charlotte; Myron, Nancy (Box 7)
  - Crazy Jane, 1977; UA156.003.007.00006 (Box 7)
    A Clark University student publication.
  - Creating a respectful environment: The challenge of inclusion, participant manual and training design, 1998; UA156.003.007.00007; Cullinan, Cris (Box 7)
    For the 11th Annual National Conference on Race and Ethnicity in American Higher Education.
  - Designing your future: A career resource book for women, 1982; UA156.003.007.00008; Governor's Commission on the Status of Women (Mass.) (Box 7)
  - Edcentric: A journal of educational reform, 1912 -- 1971; UA156.003.007.00009 (Box 7)
    From the Center for Educational Reform. Special Issue: Women in Education.
    3, 7
  - Ending cycles of violence: Integrating research, practice and social policy, 1998-11; UA156.003.007.00010 (Box 7)
    Preliminary program for The International Society for Traumatic Stress Studies 1998 Meeting.
  - Everybody's guide... to every body, 1974; UA156.003.007.00011; Planned Parenthood League of Massachusetts (Box 7)
  - Everywoman's Center annual report, 1996; UA156.003.007.00012 (Box 7)
    From the University of Massachusetts at Amherst.
  - Everywoman's Center: Evolution of an alternative, The first three Years: A herstory, 1975; UA156.003.007.00013 (Box 7)
    From the University of Massachusetts at Amherst. 1986 reprint.
  - Eve's rib, 1986; UA156.003.007.00014 (Box 7)
    A literary magazine from Barnard College.
  - Families, 1970; UA156.003.007.00015; Gordon, Linda (Box 7)
  - Feminary: A feminist journal for the South emphasizing lesbian visions, 1977 -- 1978; UA156.003.007.00016 (Box 7)
    Vol. 8, No. 2; and Vol. 9, No. 2.
  - Feminary: A feminist journal for the South emphasizing lesbian visions, 1980 -- 1982; UA156.003.007.00017 (Box 7)
    Vol. 11, Nos. 1 and 2; and Vol. 12, No. 1.
  - Feminism and Marxism, 1971; UA156.003.007.00018; Ballan, Dorothy (Box 7)
  - Feminist Alliance Against Rape newsletter, 1977; UA156.003.007.00019 (Box 7)
    March/April and September/October issues.
  - The Feminist Press: 10 years publishing women, 1970-1980, UA156.003.007.00020 (Box 7)
  - Focus: A journal for lesbians, 1978-12 -- 1979-01; UA156.003.007.00021 (Box 7)
    Published by the Boston Daughters of Bilitis.
  - For shelter and beyond: An educational manual for working with women who are battered, 1981; UA156.003.007.00022; Massachusetts Coalition of Battered Women Service Groups (Box 7)
  - Freedomways: A quarterly review of the freedom movement, 1979; UA156.003.007.00023 (Box 7)
    19, 4
  - From hearing my mother talk: stories of Cambridge women, 1979; UA156.003.007.00024; Cohen, Cindy; Acker, Bonnie (Box 7)
  - Fusion, 1970-03-20; UA156.003.007.00025; Cohen, Cindy; Acker, Bonnie (Box data_value_missing_6a278a10ccb405ecd731790260bd5f8c)
    29
  - Gay V.D.: Facts for women and men, 1970; UA156.003.007.00026; Gay Community Services Center (Los Angeles, Calif.) (Box 7)
  - Grassroots: International partnerships for change, 1986; UA156.003.007.00027 (Box data_value_missing_6a278a10ccb405ecd731790260bd5f8c)
    2, 1
  - Health care, 1972 -- 1978; UA156.003.007.00028 (Box 7)
  - [Health care - birth control pills], 1975 -- 1979; UA156.003.007.00029 (Box 7)
  - [Health care - lesbians and homosexuality], 1974 -- 1977; UA156.003.007.00030 (Box 7)
  - [Health care - menopause], 1975; UA156.003.007.00031 (Box 7)
  - [Health care - menstruation], 1977; UA156.003.007.00032 (Box 7)
  - [Health care - women and psychology], 1970 -- 1974; UA156.003.007.00033 (Box 7)
  - [Health care] women's community health, 1975 -- 1983; UA156.003.007.00034 (Box 7)
  - [Health care] women's health network, 1979 -- 1984; UA156.003.007.00035 (Box 7)
  - Health/PAC bulletin, 1977; UA156.003.007.00036 (Box 7)
    Nos. 77 and 78.
  - HealthRight, 1978; UA156.003.007.00037 (Box data_value_missing_6a278a10ccb405ecd731790260bd5f8c)
  - Higher skills, higher wages and higher achievement: A guide to nontraditional career opportunities for women, 1995; UA156.003.007.00038; Massachusetts. Division of Employment and Training; Massachusetts. Occupational Information Coordinating Committ (Box 7)
  - How to organize a multi-service women's center, 1973; UA156.003.007.00039; Shapiro, Carol (Box 7)
    From the Women's Action Alliance.
  - Institute for diversity training: Resource manual, 1998; UA156.003.007.00040; Shapiro, Carol (Box 7)
    From the 11th Annual national Conference on Race and Ethnicity in American Higher Education
  - The ladder, 1972; UA156.003.007.00041 (Box 7)
    Vol. 16, Nos. 7 - 12.
  - Lesbiana literature of women's studies, 1977; UA156.003.007.00042 (Box 7)
    This is catalog no. 1 from Alice B's Bookservice.
  - Liberating masturbation: A meditation on self love, 1974; UA156.003.007.00043; Dodson, Betty (Box 7)
  - Liberation of women: Sexual repression and the family, 1970; UA156.003.007.00044; Limpus, Laurel (Box 7)
  - Living in a house I do no own, 1982; UA156.003.007.00045; Segrest, Mab (Box 7)
  - Maenad: A women's literary journal, 1983; UA156.003.007.00046 (Box 7)
    2, 4
  - A manual for discussion leaders in the League of Women Voters, 1970; UA156.003.007.00047; Menkin, Paula (Box 7)
    This manual is missing all pages after page 19.
  - Many voices: The journal of a women's touring company at the Nairobi Conference, 1987; UA156.003.007.00048; Dodd, Elena Harap (Box 7)
  - The mole: A radical tri-weekly, 1971-04; UA156.003.007.00049; Dodd, Elena Harap (Box data_value_missing_6a278a10ccb405ecd731790260bd5f8c)
    2, 5
  - Momma, 1974; UA156.003.007.00050 (Box 7)
  - A movement of poets: Thoughts on poetry and feminism, 1982; UA156.003.007.00051; Clausen, Jan (Box 7)
  - Nachrichten aus Zehlendorf: Frauen fur den Frieden, 1984-03; UA156.003.007.00052 (Box 7)
  - Network of change-oriented foundations, 1977; UA156.003.007.00053 (Box 7)
  - The next step: A guide to part-time opportunities in Greater Boston for the educated woman, 1964; UA156.003.007.00054; White, Martha S. (Box 7)
  - New magazine, 1970; UA156.003.007.00055 (Box 7)
    Boston University student publication. This issue is titled: If you want something done, do it yourself: A women's journal.
  - New women's times, 1980-02; UA156.003.007.00056 (Box data_value_missing_6a278a10ccb405ecd731790260bd5f8c)
    6, 3
  - No more fun and games: A journal of female liberation, 1970 -- 1972; UA156.003.007.00057 (Box 7)
    Nos. 4-6.
  - Northeast College Sexual Assault Network: Membership directory and resource guide, 1998; UA156.003.007.00058 (Box 7)
  - On-the-job oppression of working women: A collection of articles, 1970; UA156.003.007.00059 (Box 7)
  - Our voice: The newsletter of women for women in Lebanon, 1984; UA156.003.007.00060 (Box 7)
    1, 2
  - People's yellow pages, 1971-11; UA156.003.007.00061 (Box 7)
    Published by Vocations for Social Change, Cambridge, MA.
  - Phoebe, 1989-10; UA156.003.007.00062 (Box 7)
    Issue on lives of women of color.
  - Radical literature from the New England Free Press, 1974-10; UA156.003.007.00063 (Box 7)
  - Rape prevention workshops: A group leader's guide, 1980; UA156.003.007.00064; Community Action Strategies to Stop Rape (Columbus, Ohio) (Box 7)
  - The real paper, 1975 -- 1977; UA156.003.007.00065 (Box data_value_missing_6a278a10ccb405ecd731790260bd5f8c)
  - Relationship violence on the college campus, 1997-10; UA156.003.008.00001 (Box 8)
    A program for a conference at Bentley College of the Massachusetts Association of College and University Public Safety Directors.
  - Report of the women's action program, 1972-01; UA156.003.008.00002 (Box 8)
    From the U.S. Department of Health, Education, and Welfare, Washington, D.C.
  - Research report, 2001; UA156.003.008.00003 (Box 8)
    From The Wellesley Centers for Women at Wellesley College.
    22, 2
  - Response to violence and sexual abuse in the family, 1979-01 -- 1979-10; UA156.003.008.00004 (Box 8)
    Vol. 2, nos. 3, 5, 7 and 9; vol. 3, no. 2. A project of the Center for Women Policy Studies.
  - Response to violence in the family, 1979-12 -- 1981-10; UA156.003.008.00005 (Box data_value_missing_6a278a10ccb405ecd731790260bd5f8c)
    Vol. 3, nos. 4, 7-8 and 10-12; Vol. 4, nos. 3, 5 and 7. A project of the Center for Women Policy Studies.
  - Response to family violence and sexual assault, 1982-01 -- 1982-10; UA156.003.008.00006 (Box 8)
    Vol. 5, nos. 1-5. A project of the Center for Women Policy Studies
  - Response to violence in the family and sexual assault, 1983 -- 1984-02; UA156.003.008.00007 (Box 8)
    Vol. 6, nos. 1-4 and 6; vol. 7, no. 1. A project of the Center for Women Policy Studies.
  - Response to the victimization of women and children, 1984 -- 1986; UA156.003.008.00008 (Box 8)
    Vol. 7, no. 4; vol. 8, no. 1; vol. 9, nos. 2-3. Journal of the Center for Women Policy Studies.
  - Revolutionary worker, 1984-03-30; UA156.003.008.00009 (Box data_value_missing_6a278a10ccb405ecd731790260bd5f8c)
    This issue is incomplete.
  - San Francisco - East Bay women's yellow pages, 1979 -- 1980; UA156.003.008.00010 (Box 8)
  - The second wave: A magazine of the new feminism, 1971 -- 1973; UA156.003.008.00011 (Box 8)
    Vol. 1, nos. 2-4; vol. 2, no. 4; vol. 3, no. 1.
  - Sex in a plain brown wrapper, 1973; UA156.003.008.00012; Student Committee on Sexuality at Syracuse University (Box 8)
  - Sex roles and female oppression, 1972; UA156.003.008.00013; Densmore, Dana (Box 8)
  - Sexual harassment and the law, 1981; UA156.003.008.00014; Dubrow, Laurie (Box 8)
    For the Alliance Against Sexual Coercion.
  - Sexually transmitted diseases (STD) and how to avoid them, 1980; UA156.003.008.00015; Lynch, Peggy; Rome, Esther (Box 8)
  - Shrew: Fiction and poetry by and about working women, 1980; UA156.003.008.00016 (Box 8)
    1, 1
  - The silent victims: Denver's battered women, 1908 -- 1977; UA156.003.008.00017; United States Commission on Civil Rights. Colorado Advisory (Box 8)
  - Sinister wisdom, 1977 -- 1979; UA156.003.008.00018 (Box 8)
    Nos. 4 and 9-10.
  - Sinister wisdom, 1979 -- 1980; UA156.003.008.00019 (Box 8)
    Nos. 11-13.
  - Sinister wisdom, 1980 -- 1981; UA156.003.008.00020 (Box 8)
    Nos. 14-16.
  - Sinister wisdom, 1981 -- 1982; UA156.003.008.00021 (Box 8)
    Nos. 18-20.
  - Sinister wisdom, 1982 -- 1983; UA156.003.008.00022 (Box 8)
    Nos. 21-23.
  - Sinister wisdom, 1983 -- 1984; UA156.003.008.00023 (Box 8)
    Nos. 24-25.
  - Sister: New Haven women's liberation newsletter, 1972-02-01; UA156.003.008.00024 (Box 8)
    1, 8
  - The sound of one fork, 1981; UA156.003.008.00025; Pratt, Minnie Bruce (Box 8)
  - Stylus, 1968 -- 1975; UA156.003.008.00026 (Box 8)
    Vol. 81, no. 2; vol. 88, no. 2.
  - Synthesis, 1980-01 -- 1981-03; UA156.003.008.00027 (Box 8)
    Vol. 7, nos. 5 and 11; vol. 8, nos. 3-4 and 7. Published by the University Women's Center at the University of Pittsburgh.
  - Synthesis, 1981-09 -- 1982-08; UA156.003.008.00028 (Box 8)
    Vol. 9, nos. 1-4, 6, and 8-11. Published by the University Women's Center at the University of Pittsburgh.
  - Synthesis, 1982-09 -- 1983-01; UA156.003.008.00029 (Box 8)
    Vol. 10, nos. 1-3. Published by the University Women's Center at the University of Pittsburgh.
  - To reclaim a legacy of diversity: Analyzing the 'political correctness' debates in higher education, 1993; UA156.003.008.00030; Schultz, Debra L. (Box 8)
    A report prepared by the National Council for Research on Women.
  - Trivia: A journal of ideas, 1982 -- 1983; UA156.003.008.00031 (Box 8)
    Nos. 1-2.
  - Trivia: A journal of ideas, 1983 -- 1984; UA156.003.008.00032 (Box 8)
    Nos. 3 and 5.
  - The turning point III: Writings from MCI Framingham, 1977; UA156.003.008.00033 (Box 8)
  - Two studies of women in higher education, 1974-05; UA156.003.008.00034; Bertelsen, Judy (Box 8)
    I. Impact of coeducation on colleges previously for women only, and II. Women's center survey.
  - Valley women's studies journal, 1973; UA156.003.008.00035 (Box 8)
    From Mount Holyoke College.
  - VD claptrap, 1972-10-09; UA156.003.008.00036; Gordon, Sol; Conant, Roger (Box 8)
  - VD handbook, 1977-04; UA156.003.008.00037; Cherniak, Donna; Feingold, Allan (Box 8)
  - We are all lesbians: A poetry anthology, 1973; UA156.003.008.00038 (Box 8)
  - Who is Norma Jean Serena?, 1976; UA156.003.008.00039 (Box 8)
  - Will the circle be unbroken: A people's guide to grand juries and FBI harassment, 1975; UA156.003.008.00040 (Box 8)
  - The woman alcoholic, 1975; UA156.003.008.00041; Lindbeck, Vera (Box 8)
  - A woman is talking to death, 1974; UA156.003.008.00042; Grahn, Judy; Sjo'holm, Karen (Box 8)
  - The woman rebel: The magazine for the female iconoclast, 1994; UA156.003.008.00043 (Box 8)
  - Womanpower newsletter, 1975-02; UA156.003.008.00044 (Box 8)
    Employer's monthly report on equal opportunity for women.
    General
    On March 30, 2016 UA156.003.008.00044, Womanpower newsletter was found to be not in the box by Rose Oliveira. This box was pulled for class visit. All boxes for the class were checked but the folder was not found.
  - A woman's book: Tufts, 1976; UA156.003.008.00045; Levertov, Denise; 0.1 Linear Feet 2 copies (Box 8)
    Includes a history of women at Tufts and information about the Mellon Grant.
    Immediate Source of Acquisition
    Second Copy: Transferred by Tisch Library, 2022, accession MS-2020-023.
    Custodial History
    Second copy was gifted to Tisch Library by Professor Hilary Binda, then transferred to DCA by Tisch Library.
  - Women and justice: blind no more, 1981-04; UA156.003.008.00046 (Box 8)
    The 12th National Conference on Women and the Law registration catalog.
  - Women and literature, 1976; UA156.003.008.00047; Vanlaecken, Mireille M. (Box 8)
    This is a catalog from Christian F. Verbeke Rare Books, Inc.
  - Women and socialism, 1972; UA156.003.008.00048 (Box 8)
    Contains two articles: 'Women in the Liberation Struggle - An Overview'; and 'Ma Bell Has Fleas - and a Lot of Angry Workers.'
  - Women at Tufts University: A preliminary inquiry, 1972-12 -- 1979; UA156.003.009.00001; Green, Stephanie; Landsberger, Ellen; Martens, Kay; Simmons, Adele; Simon, Terri (Box 9)
    This folder also contains documents regarding union organization at Tufts, 1978-1979, that were enclosed with the publication.
  - Women in distribution: Autumn catalog, 1975; UA156.003.009.00002 (Box 9)
  - Women in the struggle for liberation, 1975; UA156.003.009.00003 (Box 9)
    From the World Student Christian Federation Book Series, serial number 8/9, vol. 3, no. 2/3, 1973. Revised 1975.
  - Women: Their present situation in the world, the need for liberation of all women, the difficulties and the opportunities, detailed proposals for policies and actions, 1984-10; UA156.003.009.00004 (Box 9)
    Summary report of the International Women's Conference of the Re-evaluation Counseling Communities held in the Netherlands.
  - Women workers: Some basic statistics, 1971; UA156.003.009.00005; Vogel, Lise (Box 9)
  - The Women's Center communal meal cookbook, 2009 -- 2010; UA156.003.009.00006; Levertov, Denise (Box 9)
    From the Tufts University Women's Center.
  - Women's Community Health Center annual report, 5th anniversary issue, 1979; UA156.003.009.00007 (Box 9)
  - Women's network directory, 1980; UA156.003.009.00008 (Box 9)
    For the Greater Boston area
  - A women's poetry reading, 1972; UA156.003.009.00009 (Box 9)
    This is a project of the Ain't I A Woman Collective.
  - Women's yellow pages, 1972; UA156.003.009.00010; Public Works, inc. (Box 9)
    Published by the Boston Women's Collective (now known as Public Works, Inc.). Includes a critical look at health care, practical self defense, legal advice on divorce, adoption, continuing education, and job training.
  - Women's yellow pages: Original source book for women, 1974; UA156.003.009.00011; Public Works, inc. (Box 9)
    Published by the Boston Women's Collective (now known as Public Works, inc.).
  - WomenWise: The N.H. feminist health center quarterly, 1978 -- 1984; UA156.003.009.00012 (Box 9)
    Vol. 1, no. 4; vol. 3, nos. 2-4; vol. 4, no. 1; vol. 7, no. 3.
  - Working women: Our stories and struggles, 1970; UA156.003.009.00013 (Box 9)
- Web crawls, 2015 -- 2020; UA156.004; 1 Web sites
  Quarterly web crawls of the SAGE - Students Acting for Gender Equality website crawled by DCA, as part of the Student Organizations web collection, to document the presesence of Tufts University student organizations on the web.
  Other Finding Aids
  To see all of websites crawled as part of the Student Organizations web collection, please visit https://archive-it.org/collections/6387
  - SAGE - Students Acting for Gender Equality, 2015 -- 2020; UA156.004.00001; Women's Center, Tufts University
    Frequency: quarterly crawl.
- Additional accessions, UA156.005
  - Women's Center digital files, 2008 -- 2012; UA156-001
    20 years from date of creation.
  - Cookbook, newsletters and flow charts, 2002 -- 2012; UA156-002 (Box 1)
  - Women's Center posters, undated, UA156-003 (Box 2)
  - Office files, 2000 -- 2007; UA156.000674 (Box 3)
  - Floppy Discs, CDs, Zip Files, 2000 -- 2007; UA156-005 (Box Shared 8)
  - Orientation '97, 1997; UA156-006
  - Women's forum - 10 year anniversary, 1994 -- 1998; UA156-007
  - Orientation, 1996 -- 1997; UA156-008
  - Asian American alumni reception, 2000 -- 2004; UA156-009
  - In the Sack, 2007; UA156-010
  - In the Sack, 2007; UA156-011
  - Many Stories One Community, 1998; UA156-012
  - Women's Center 1998-1999 brochure, UA156-013
  - Women's programs budget, 1998; UA156-014
  - Alcohol and health budget, 1996 -- 1998; UA156-015
  - CDC budgets, 1996; UA156-016
  - Asian American Center, 1997 -- 1998; UA156-017
  - Asian American Center budget, 2000 -- 2001; UA156-018
  - Budgets 2004 – 2005, 2003--2004; UA156.019; 43 Digital Object(s)
  - 2001 -2002 1 of 2, 2001--2003; UA156.020; 402 Digital Object(s)
  - Zip disks, 2004 -- 2005; UA156.000676; 2 Digital Object(s) 2 Zip disks (Box Shared Digital Media 2)
- 2017 accessions, 1980 -- 2017; UA156.006; 1.2 Linear Feet 1 record carton; 7 Folder(s)
  This series is open for research.
  Transferred by the Women's Center, 2017, accession UA-2018-006.
  This series is arranged in received order.
  This series contains event posters, newsletters of the Women's Center from the early 1980s, and videotapes of events and speakers at the Women's Center.
  - Posters and newsletters, 1980 -- 2010; UA156.006.013; 1 Folder(s) (Box 2)
    This folder includes general and event posters from 1982-2010, and the newsletter of the Women's Center, "Women Centered," from 1980-1981.
  - Videotapes, 1990 -- 2003; UA156.006.014; 1.2 Linear Feet 1 record container (Box 14)
    This box contains videotapes of events and speakers including Senior Talks, Asian American Peer Leader Skits, Rape Awareness, and Many Stories, as well as other videotapes kept at the Women's Center.
  - Projects, posters, photographs, circa 2010 -- 2017; UA156.006.015; 6 Folder(s) (Box 15)
    These folders include posters for events including Feminist Reading Group, Dinner and a Movie, and First Friday Lunch.